<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-06-27T19:49:38+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Ujjawal Annad</title><subtitle>Android Developer</subtitle><entry><title type="html">My Review of the Best Books I Read in 2016</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Book-Review-2016/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Review of the Best Books I Read in 2016" /><published>2017-02-02T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-02-02T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Book-Review-2016</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Book-Review-2016/">&lt;p&gt;I took a challenge of reading &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/user/year_in_books/2016/24629386&quot;&gt;20 books in 2016&lt;/a&gt; of which I successfully
completed 13 books. I mostly prefer non-fiction because they focus more on how the real world works and
give me most out of the time I invest in them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From creative process at Pixar to the life of real world wizard - Elon Musk, I learned a lot
from them. Below is the short review of books I like the most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mans-search-for-meaning--by-viktor-e-frankl&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/4069.Man_s_Search_for_Meaning&quot;&gt;Man’s Search for Meaning&lt;/a&gt; -By Viktor E. Frankl&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Everything can be taken from a man but one thing: the last
of the human freedoms–to choose one’s attitude in any given
set of circumstances, to choose one’s own way.” -Frankl&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book discusses Frankl’s experiences in Auschwitz and other
concentration camps as well as his experiences afterward, with
an eye toward figuring out the meaning of life. Despite what
seems a dismal topic, this is a optimistic book that left me
feeling satisfied and joyful. Frankl believes that life can
have meaning at all times and under all circumstances, and he
makes a convincing argument. I plan to recommend this book to
my friends and to read it again&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-hard-thing-about-hard-things-building-a-business-when-there-are-no-easy-answers-by-ben-horowitz&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18176747-the-hard-thing-about-hard-things&quot;&gt;The Hard Thing About Hard Things: Building a Business When There Are No Easy Answers&lt;/a&gt; By Ben Horowitz&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just loved this book and will like to recommend it
to anyone who has hunch to start a company (just to be aware
of the fact that how hard it is) or even a part of a startup
company as it really helps you to understand the never lasting
 demanding nature of startups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with other available books on same topic is,
 they are written by authors who have not the first hand
 experience of starting a company from scratch and sailing it
 to the very end, successfully, the people who have never managed
 even a fruit stand in their life. Some of them try to sell you
 some formulas, shortcuts on starting a company (there is no such thing
 like that) while some of them clearly don’t have any idea what
 are they talking about and end up sounding like a fairy tale with rainbows and sunshine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not saying all of them are bad (peace!!) but when someone
like Ben Horowitz who just didn’t create a company from scratch
but sail it through worst economic recession, specially for an
internet based company i.e dot-com bubble burst to the very
end(selling it to HP), writes a book on the same topic it clearly
blows out everything else out of the water.
What I like the most about this book is it’s detailed nature,
Ben just doesn’t only talk about why some strategy is bad for you
 company but also gives you an example (a real one) and then goes
  further and talks about what you should be doing instead i.e the
   right strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following is some excerpts from book which I find worth mentioning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Perhaps the most important thing that I learned as an entrepreneur was to focus on what I needed to get right and stop worrying about all the things that I did wrong or might do wrong”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“By far the most difficult skill that I learned as CEO was the ability to manage my own psychology. Organisational design, process design, metrics, hiring and firing were all relatively straightforward skills to master compared with keeping my mind in check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“It’s like the fight club of management. The first rule of the CEO psychological meltdown is don’t talk about the psychological meltdown”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Great CEOs face the pain. They deal with the sleepless nights, the cold sweats, and what my friend Alfred Chuang calls “the torture”. Whenever I meet a successful CEO, I ask them how they did it.Mediocre CEOs point to their brilliant strategic moves or their intuitive business sense or a variety of other self-congratulatory explanations. The great CEOs tend to be remarkably consistent in their answers. They all say, ‘I didn’t quit’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Every time you make the hard, correct decision you become a bit more courageous and every time you make the easy, wrong decision you become a bit more cowardly. If you are a CEO, these choices will lead to a courageous or cowardly company”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Hard things are hard because there are no easy answers or recipes. They are hard because your emotions are at odds with your logic. They are hard because you cannot ask for help without showing weakness”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;” ‘Life is struggle.’ I believe that within that quote lies the most important lesson in entrepreneurship: Embrace the struggle.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;creativity-inc-overcoming-the-unseen-forces-that-stand-in-the-way-of-true-inspiration-by-ed-catmull-amy-wallace&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/18077903-creativity-inc&quot;&gt;Creativity, Inc.: Overcoming the Unseen Forces That Stand in the Way of True Inspiration&lt;/a&gt; By Ed Catmull, Amy Wallace&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a Pixar fan to my core and this book only reinforced my
 connection. Their films are the outcome of a beautiful
 collaboration among a diverse group of talented individuals.
 Ed’s compilation of the ups and downs of Pixar shows the power
 of heeding to principles not focused on profits,
 but on daring to do the best, most creative work you can.
 It is so crucial to create an environment where failure is not
 just acceptable, but expected when daring to do something hard
 and worth doing. I am inspired and enlightened by their
 learning and commitment to each other. If I were to start my
 own company, this would be the handbook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bonus was hearing his experience working
Steve Jobs, and gratifying to know that Ed, Steve and John
Lasseter all grew as leaders in the time the took Pixar
from good to great&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;elon-musk-inventing-the-future-by-ashlee-vance&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/22543496-elon-musk&quot;&gt;Elon Musk: Inventing the Future&lt;/a&gt; By Ashlee Vance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being an Elon Musk fanboy, I have watched countless interviews
and read a lot about him over the web. This book is an yet
another quest in knowing about musk on an even more deeper level.
Ashlee Vance has done a fantastic job of getting the reader
absorbed into every intricate details about Elon. Moreover,
it din’t actually feel like reading a book .
But, like sitting intrigued for long hours listening to a
close friend of Elon speak about him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-power-of-habit-why-we-do-what-we-do-in-life-and-business-by-charles-duhigg&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12609433-the-power-of-habit&quot;&gt;The Power of Habit: Why We Do What We Do in Life and Business&lt;/a&gt; By Charles Duhigg&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a great book and some of the facts and stories are really
great and cool enough to be part of a discussion or things
you wana talk about while you are on a date (nerd alert).
 The book is really impressive especially the habits of
 individuals section of the book inspires and motivates
 me a lot to follow the wonderful statements given in the
 book how to work with habit loop using cue routine reward
 pattern to create new and change existing habits to be
 satisfied in whatever habits that we are involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing that I didn’t like about this book is the authors’s writing stile,
the way he stretches the story, keeps fixating on same
fact even after making the point and starts another story
in middle of one. And this is why I left reading it after
first section (which is really interesting).
The better strategy to read this book, without being bored
would be to read the first section and then select the
section you wana read about by going through contents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-100-startup-reinvent-the-way-you-make-a-living-do-what-you-love-and-create-a-new-future-by-chris-guillebeau&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/12605157-the-100-startup&quot;&gt;The $100 Startup: Reinvent the Way You Make a Living, Do What You Love, and Create a New Future&lt;/a&gt; By Chris Guillebeau&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we hear word entrepreneurship, name of people like Bill Gates
Mark Zuckerberg, Elon Musk and their multi billion ventures
come in mind at the same time. &lt;br /&gt;
However, there is also example of people who didn’t need a great idea, venture capital or even a detailed plan, they
just went on to solve their own problem and by doing this they
found their own business to support their life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this book, author Chris Guillebeau has collected some case studies
on those very people and their business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the words of Chris Guillebeau himself, “It’s a Blueprint, Not a Vague Series of Ideas”.
This book offers you the blueprint to kickstart a microbusiness, showing you to get from Point A to Point B. If you’re trying to look for business ideas, or even ideas to improve your business, this may not be the best book to pick up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, if you’re looking for a guide on starting a microbusiness, I believe this is a great guide that will serve you well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing I like about this book is how much it talks about value (helping others).
Keep in mind that the goal of a business is profit. To reach profitability? Consider how much value you’re adding to other people’s life.
It’s my personal opinion that a lot of business today are so profit-oriented they forgot about the value they are providing to customers.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I took a challenge of reading 20 books in 2016 of which I successfully completed 13 books. I mostly prefer non-fiction because they focus more on how the real world works and give me most out of the time I invest in them.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Favourite Read From The Past - Startups, Tech. Life</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Top-Reads-2016/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Favourite Read From The Past - Startups, Tech. Life" /><published>2017-01-31T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-01-31T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Top-Reads-2016</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Top-Reads-2016/">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Reading is to the mind what exercise is to the body.&lt;br /&gt;
-Joseph Addision&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the habits I grew in myself which I am really proud of and really goes into making the person I am today is: &lt;strong&gt;Learning a lot of things by Reading a lot of things.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
In course of time, I’ve consumed many articles (mostly on Internet) and have bookmarked the one I like the most. The following is a list of some of my favourite articles from the past year in no particular order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d encourage you to scroll through the entire list and read the ones that seem interesting to you. And feel free to share what you loved to read this year&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;teach-yourself-programming-in-10-years&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://norvig.com/21-days.html&quot;&gt;Teach yourself programming in 10 years&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The key is deliberative practice: not just doing it again and again, but challenging yourself with a task that is just beyond your current ability, trying it, analyzing your performance while and after doing it, and correcting any mistakes. Then repeat. And repeat again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;the-reductive-seduction-of-other-peoples-problem--&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://thedevelopmentset.com/the-reductive-seduction-of-other-people-s-problems-3c07b307732d#.40qkr1ptl&quot;&gt;The reductive seduction of other people’s problem.  &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A well written, and urgently needed analysis of the relationship between American youth (or say any first world country’s youth) and the world of international development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;how-to-stop-giving-f-what-people-think---start-living-your-life&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/life-hacking-2/how-to-stop-giving-a-f-what-people-think-46bf86584c95&quot;&gt;How to stop giving f@&amp;amp;% what people think - start living your life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Start standing up for what you believe in — causes, opinions, anything. You’re going to have people that disagree with you anyways, so why not express how you truly feel?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;an-engineers-guide-to-stock-option&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.alexmaccaw.com/an-engineers-guide-to-stock-options&quot;&gt;An engineer’s guide to stock option&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This guide is an attempt to correct some of the imbalance in information between companies and employees, and explain in plain English the whole stock option process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;so-you-want-to-work-in-security-&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.freecodecamp.com/so-you-want-to-work-in-security-bc6c10157d23&quot;&gt;So, you want to work in security? &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A helpful and insightful article from Parisa Tabriz - head of Google Chrome security team, to anyone who wants to work in security field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;what-happens-when-&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alex/what-happens-when&quot;&gt;What happens when &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;An attempt to answer the age old interview question “What happens when you type google.com into your browser’s address box and press enter?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;an-open-guide-to-equity-compensation&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jlevy/og-equity-compensation&quot;&gt;An open guide to equity compensation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;More like a small book, trying to explain a rather very confusing topic: &lt;em&gt;Equity Compensation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;an-introduction-to-stock-market&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://invento.quora.com/Introduction-to-Finance-Stock-Markets?share=1&amp;amp;srid=iGUX&quot;&gt;An introduction to stock market&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A very helpful post to make you understand the basics of stock market from none other than Quora Rockstart &lt;strong&gt;Balaji Viswanathan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;emotional-intelligence-the-social-skills-you-werent-taught-in-school&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/emotional-intelligence-the-social-skills-you-werent-ta-1697704987?utm_source=pocket&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=pockethits&quot;&gt;Emotional Intelligence: The Social Skills You Weren’t Taught in School&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A helpful guide regarding how to identify or deal with our own emotions, or the emotions of others&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;how-to-negotiate-nicely-without-being-a-pushover&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2015/04/how-to-negotiate-nicely-without-being-a-pushover?utm_source=pocket&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=pockethits&quot;&gt;How to Negotiate Nicely Without Being a Pushover&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How exactly do you drive a hard bargain while also employing soft skills? How do you advocate for what you want without burning important bridges? How? Read the article to find out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;10-tricks-to-appear-smart-during-meetings-&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/conquering-corporate-america/10-tricks-to-appear-smart-during-meetings-27b489a39d1a&quot;&gt;10 tricks to appear smart during meetings &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Sometimes meetings can be difficult if you start daydreaming about your next vacation, your next nap, or bacon. When this happens, it’s good to have some fallback tricks to fall back on&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;how-quitting-my-corporate-job-for-my-startup-dream-fcked-my-life-up-&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/swlh/how-quitting-my-corporate-job-for-my-startup-dream-f-cked-my-life-up-3b6b3e29b318&quot;&gt;How quitting my corporate job for my startup dream f*cked my life up &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Day by day, I was getting lonelier and more depressive as I avoided social occasions. My startup progress was not as fast as my social circle imagined it to be and I was fed up with telling people it took years for startups like Facebook and Twitter to arrive at where they are now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;how-to-start-a-startup&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.superhi.com/blog/how-to-start-a-startup-without-ruining-your-life&quot;&gt;How to start a startup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Startups are emotional roller coasters that one minute make you feel like you’re changing the world and the next minute, that everything is falling apart. This guide about how to start a startup may help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;15-tricks-to-appear-smart-in-emails-&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/conquering-corporate-america/15-tricks-to-appear-smart-in-emails-608f5cf27975&quot;&gt;15 Tricks to Appear Smart in Emails &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Your email writing, sending and ignoring skills are just as important as your nodding skills, and even more important than your copying and pasting skills. Here are 15 email tricks that will make you appear smart, passionate, dedicated and most of all, smart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;the-science-of-why-you-should-spend-your-time-on-expriences-not-thing-&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastcompany.com/3043858/world-changing-ideas/the-science-of-why-you-should-spend-your-money-on-experiences-not-thing?utm_source=pocket&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=pockethits&quot;&gt;The science of why you should spend your time on expriences not thing &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We know that money can make you happier, though after your basic needs are met, it doesn’t make you that much happier. But one of the biggest questions is how to allocate our money, which is (for most of us) a limited resource.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;7-rules-for-creating-gorgeous-ui-part-1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@erikdkennedy/7-rules-for-creating-gorgeous-ui-part-1-559d4e805cda&quot;&gt;7 Rules for Creating Gorgeous UI (Part 1)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;An UI/UX design guide for nerds - part 1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;7-rules-for-creating-gorgeous-ui-part-2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@erikdkennedy/7-rules-for-creating-gorgeous-ui-part-2-430de537ba96&quot;&gt;7 Rules for Creating Gorgeous UI (Part 2)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;An UI?UX design for nerds - part 2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;how-i-learned-to-stop-procrastinating--love-letting-go&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://zenhabits.net/leggo/&quot;&gt;How I Learned to Stop Procrastinating, &amp;amp; Love Letting Go&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Zen way to stop Procrastinating, really helpul guide to achieve life long success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;relearning-the-art-of-asking-questions-&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/2015/03/relearning-the-art-of-asking-questions?utm_source=pocket&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_campaign=pockethits&quot;&gt;Relearning the Art of Asking Questions &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Asking clarifying questions can help uncover the real intent behind what is said. These help us understand each other better and lead us toward relevant follow-up questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;google-cfo-retires-with-a-candid-memo-about-worklife-balance&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mashable.com/2015/03/10/googles-cfo-retires-memo/#e5IbFn5k3kqA&quot;&gt;Google CFO retires with a candid memo about work/life balance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In the end, life is wonderful, but nonetheless a series of trade offs, especially between business/professional endeavours and family/community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;great-hackers&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.paulgraham.com/gh.html&quot;&gt;Great Hackers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I know a handful of super-hackers, so I sat down and thought about what they have in common. Their defining quality is probably that they really love to program. Ordinary programmers write code to pay the bills. Great hackers think of it as something they do for fun, and which they’re delighted to find people will pay them for. - Paul Graham, founder of YC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;books-worth-reading-as-recommended-by-bill-gates-susan-cain-and-more-&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ideas.ted.com/books-worth-reading-this-holiday-recommended-by-bill-gates-susan-cain-and-more/&quot;&gt;Books worth reading, as recommended by Bill Gates, Susan Cain and more… &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A curated list ofrecommended books from great personalities&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;advice-for-ambitious-19-year-olds&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.samaltman.com/advice-for-ambitious-19-year-olds&quot;&gt;Advice for ambitious 19 year olds&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;From Sam Altman, &lt;em&gt;President of Y Combinator&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;good-and-bad-reasons-to-become-an-entrepreneur&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/i-m-h-o/good-and-bad-reasons-to-become-an-entrepreneur-decf0766de8d&quot;&gt;Good and Bad Reasons to Become an Entrepreneur&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Some valuable insights on being Entrepreneur from Dustin Moskovitz, &lt;em&gt;cofounder of facebook&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;what-i-tell-all-new-programmers&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://josephg.com/blog/what-i-tell-all-new-programmers/&quot;&gt;What I tell all new programmers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;An assorted set of wisdom to all new programmers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;what-is-your-favourite-productivity-hack-&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.forbes.com/sites/quora/2014/05/19/as-a-startup-ceo-what-is-your-favorite-productivity-hack/#717c75ca6887&quot;&gt;What is your favourite productivity hack? &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Invaluable insights to control your life and get the best out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;why-learning-to-code-is-so-damn-hard&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vikingcodeschool.com/posts/why-learning-to-code-is-so-damn-hard&quot;&gt;Why learning to code is so damn hard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What every beginner absolutely needs to know about the journey ahead&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;this-is-your-brain-on-mobile&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@jgvandehey/this-is-your-brain-on-mobile-15308056cfae&quot;&gt;This is your brain on mobile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A critique of destructive smartphone habits diagnosed by someone that makes a living off of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;the-real-10-algorithms-that-dominate-our-world&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@_marcos_otero/the-real-10-algorithms-that-dominate-our-world-e95fa9f16c04&quot;&gt;The real 10 algorithms that dominate our world&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Maybe a little more than 10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;9-things-i-learned-as-a-software-engineer&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@maebert/9-things-i-learned-as-a-software-engineer-c2c9f76c9266&quot;&gt;9 Things I Learned as a Software Engineer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This is a note to the younger self, a list of things author learned, sometimes painfully, in the past three years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Reading is to the mind what exercise is to the body. -Joseph Addision</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Up and running, Hell Ya!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Hello-World/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Up and running, Hell Ya!" /><published>2017-01-30T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2017-01-30T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Hello-World</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Hello-World/">&lt;p&gt;I had previously tried to create my own blog enabled website but becuase of the amount of work it requires to create such site (we are talking about a well maintained backend with database and all), I couldn’t bring this idea in action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Few months went by and one day I was just reading about a blog and in the footer of of the same, I saw “Powered by Jekyll”.So out of curiosity I google “Jekyll” and went through first few links, all of them saying, more or less the same thing that “Jekyll is really cool and with help of it you can create your own blog in very few steps”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward yesteday (29 Jan 2017) I thought to give it a try and started with the documentation and all. And after 8 straight hours, here I am writing my first blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Tom Preston-Werner (creator of Jekyll) and the entire team behind “Jekyll” for this amazing piece of software.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I had previously tried to create my own blog enabled website but becuase of the amount of work it requires to create such site (we are talking about a well maintained backend with database and all), I couldn’t bring this idea in action.</summary></entry></feed>